A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, East European Fund FA747
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, East European Fund
1947-1961
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA747
15.6 Cubic Feet 13 boxes.
13 boxes.
Biographical/Historical note
The East European Fund was established by the Ford Foundation for the general purpose of assisting recent exiles from the Soviet Union in their adjustment to and integration into American life. This particular program of scholarship awards was designed to assist the qualified Ukrainian and Byelorussian students in this exile group whose higher education was disrupted by World War II.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for scholarly research, with select individual files restricted, as noted.
RAC is unable to provide access to obsolete media and original digital media. In addition separated media may not yet have undergone stabilization procedures. When feasible, a digital surrogate may be created via special order. All applicable charges will apply. See RAC Head of Archival Services or RAC Head of Digital Programs for details.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series:
Series I: Organizational records. Series II: Administrative Files. Series III: Community Files. Series IV: Grant Files. Series V: Scholarship Program.
Scope and Contents
Contains: Organizational records, Administrative Files, Community Files, Grant Files and documentation of the Scholarship Program.
Separated Materials
Special format items (audio, film, video, digital media, library materials, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Ford Foundation
- Organizational Records, 1950-1961; I
  Scope and Contents note
  The Organizational Records consist of Board of Trustee files, including information about the members, meeting minutes, and correspondence. This series also contains bylaws, organizational planning records, and legal documents.
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, includes index, 1951; 2 folders. (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, 1952; 2 folders. (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, 1953; 2 folders. (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Meeting minutes, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Officers - Altschul, Frank, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Officers - Anderson, Paul B., 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Officers - Fainsod, Merle, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Officers - Kennon, George F., 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Officers - Mosley, Phillip E., 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Officers - Wasson, R. Gordon, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees - Officers - Wood, John E.F., 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - By-Laws, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - Name change - Free Russia Fund to East European Fund, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Incorporation - Free Russia Fund, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Legal files - tax documents, Act of Assignment, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - Plans - first draft of "Major Projects for Soviet Refugees in the US", 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - Plans, 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Trustees - Kennan, George F. - clippings (Box 13)
- Administrative Files, 1948-1961; II
  Arrangement note
  The Administrative Files have been divided into two subseries – General Administrative files and Subject Files.
  These files document the daily running of the East European Fund. The Administrative Files have been divided into two subseries – General Administrative files and Subject Files. The General Administrative files contain correspondence between the EEF and universities and organizations, such as the United Ukrainian American Relief Committee, Ukrainian Women Alliance, Russian Student Fund and Free Russian Youth Club to confirm payments for scholarship grants to various scholarship awardees. The Subject Files highlight areas such as the arts that the EEF was associated with, specifically the American Committee for Émigré Scholars, Writers and Artists.
  - General files, 1951-1961; II_A
    - Accounts - Memoranda from Ford, 1952 (Box 1)
    - American Council on Education - conference program and report on services, 1952 (Box 1)
    - American Foundation News Service, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
    - City Projects - Administrative, 1952-1954 (Box 1)
    - City Projects - General, 1952-1954 (Box 1)
    - Eastern European Fund Conference, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
    - English Language Training, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    - Financial Statements, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
    - Financial Statements, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
    - Financial Statements, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Financial Statements, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
    - Grants - cash requests to Ford Foundation, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Grants - central office revised budget, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Grants - central office summary of authorizations and expenses, 1954-1958 (Box 2)
    - Grants - grant procedure, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Grants - program and budget requests, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Grants - program and budget requests, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Grants - schedule grant applications received from Ford Foundation, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - New York Regional Conference, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Bosworth, Francis, 1954 (Box 2)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted from scholarly access - personnel material
    - Personnel - Beckendorf, Edith, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Cassidy, Florence, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - DeWolf, Rachel, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Downing, Ruth, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Elliot, Anne, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Fjetland, O.K., 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Gwyn, Marian, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Keller, Mary, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Kobiashvili, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Lowrie, Donald A., 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Meredith, Elizabeth, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Munford, David Charles, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Plante, Lillian Dillon, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Ruggles, Melville J., 1952 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Salvin, Marina, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Personnel - Inactive, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Quarterly Reports - Cassidy memos, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Trustee Tea - guest list, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Subject files, 1948-1956; II_B
    - A - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - Alverdy - Caucasian Society, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - American Committee for Emigre Scholars, Writers, Artists, 1950-1952 (Box 2)
    - American Committee for Emigre Scholars, Writers, Artists, 1953 (Box 2)
    - American Committee for Emigre Scholars, Writers, Artists, 1954 (Box 2)
    - American Committee for Free Russia, Inc (Gourevitch), 1952 (Box 2)
    - American Committee for Liberation from Belshevism, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - American Federation of International Institutes, 1953 (Box 2)
    - American Friends of Russian Freedom, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - American Language Center for Foreign Students, 1951 (Box 2)
    - Ar - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - Archimovitsch, Alexander Z., 1953 (Box 2)
    - Association of Ukrainian Writers, MUR, 1952 (Box 2)
    - B - Miscellaneous, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Belosselsky, Serge S., 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Bibliography - Fund Research Projectg, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Bohatirchuk, Fedor, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Bosworth Trip, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Byelorussian-American Students Association, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - Byelorussian Students Association in the USA, 1952-1954 (Box 2)
    - Byelorussian Youth Association of America, 1952-1953 (Box 2)
    - C - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - Canadian Organizations and Requests, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Canadian Society for Aid to East European Refugees (CSAEER), 1953 (Box 2)
    - Chekhov Publishing House - Advisory Committee, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - Chekhov Publishing House - General, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - Chekhov Publishing House - Reports, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Chekhov Publishing House - Request for extension to 1956, 1951-1956 (Box 2)
    - Chekhov Review Committee, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Churches, 1951-1954 (Box 2)
    - Chyz, Yaroslav J., 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Conference of Ukranian Students Associations of America, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Congressional Record, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Cossacks - Representative of Cossacks former displaced persons, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Cossack Organizations, 1951-1953 (Box 2)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1952 (Box 2)
    - Cox Committee, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Cox Committee Questionnaire, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - D - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Denicke, George, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Der Monat, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Displaced Persons Legislation, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Dorbus, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
    - E - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Eastern Quarterly, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
    - Efremov, Dr. Nicholas, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Eleneff, Dr. Nicholas, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - F - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Fellowship and Scholarship Information - general, 1954 (Box 3)
    - Fellowship and Scholarship Information - EEF and FF, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Fordham University, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Free Europe Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Free Europe University in Exile, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - Friendship Houses, Inc., 1952 (Box 3)
    - Freund, Vera, 1953 (Box 3)
    - Fund for Adult Education, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - Fund for the Advancement of Education - press releases, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Freedom Union for German-Russian Friendship, 1951 (Box 3)
    - G - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Gourevitch, 1945-1952 (Box 3)
    - Granovsky, Professor A.A., 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - H - Miscellaneous, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
    - Hairenik Publications (Armenian), 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Handbook for Exile Groups - documentation and handbooks (2 folders), 1952 (Box 3)
    - Hazen, Edward W. (Foundation), 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Hoffman, Paul, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Humenna, Jokiya - "The Great Tzabbee", 1953 (Box 3)
    - I - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Initial Reception - Displaced Persons, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - Institute on International Education, 1952 (Box 3)
    - Intercultural Publications, 1953 (Box 3)
    - International Refugee Organization, 1951 (Box 3)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - J - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - K - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Karpovich, Michael, 1951-1952 (Box 3)
    - L - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Labor Temple, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - Libraries, 1951-1953 (Box 3)
    - Luckyj, George - Study of Ukranian DP Politics, 1951 (Box 3)
    - M - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Margolin, 1952-1954 (Box 3)
    - Methodist Committee for Overseas Relief, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - Mid-European Studies Center, 1952-1953 (Box 3)
    - Munich Institute, 1951 (Box 3)
    - N - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 3)
    - Nabokov, Nicholas, 1951 (Box 3)
    - National Conference of Social Work, 1952 (Box 3)
    - National Conference of Social Work, 1953 (Box 3)
    - National Conference of Social Work, 1954 (Box 3)
    - National Council on Nationalization and Citizenship 1954 (2 folders), 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - National Council on Nationalization and Citezenship 1953, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - National Information Bureau, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - National Social Welfare Assembly, 1953 (Box 4)
    - New School of Social Research, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Nicolaevsky, Boris I., 1951 (Box 4)
    - Non-Governmental Agencies Conference on Migration, 1952-1953 (Box 4)
    - Novo-Diveevo - Russion Orthodox convent, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
    - North Caucasian Association in the USA, Inc., 1952-1954 (Box 4)
    - O - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Order of the Former Russian Military, Inc., 1951-1952 (Box 4)
    - Overseas training and research, 1952-1954 (Box 4)
    - P - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Paterson, Inc., 1951 (Box 4)
    - Patterson and Ridgeway, 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - Personnel Rosters, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Press clips, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Press notices, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Press Releases, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Program in support of Slavic publication in the US, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Providence, RI - International Institute, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Publicity, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - R Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Radio, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Radio Free Europe, 1951-1952 (Box 4)
    - Reece, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Refugees, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Research program on the USSR - Request for extenstion, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Resources for the Future, 1953 (Box 4)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Russian American Union for Protection and Aid to Russians Outside of Russia, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
    - Russian Children's Welfare Society, 1951 (Box 4)
    - Russian Emigre Politics Distribution, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Russian Institute, 1952-1953 (Box 4)
    - Russian Recordings - Columbia University, 1952-1953 (Box 4)
    - Russian Organizations - other, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
    - Russian Orthodox Cathedral of the Holy Virgin Protection - Nicholas Afonsky, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - S - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 4)
    - Sbonr, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Self-reliance - Ukraine, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
    - Shteppa, Konstantin F. - Fund for Intellectual Freedom, 1951-1952 (Box 4)
    - Siegel, Ada, 1951-1952 (Box 4)
    - Society of New Russian Immigrants in the US, 1951-1952 (Box 4)
    - Society of Russian Immigrants, Boston, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
    - Sollogub, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
    - Solonevitch, Boris, 1951-1953 (Box 5)
    - Soviet Science Project - Survey, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
    - Syracuse University - USAFIT Proposal, 1952 (Box 5)
    - T - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - The Tschaikowsky Foundation, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
    - U Miscellaneous, 1951-1953 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian American Publishing Company, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Bandurist Chorus, Michigan, 1949-1953 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Book Club, Winnipeg, Manitoba - Canada, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Book Publishing Project, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Book Publishing Project - Business matters, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Book Publishing Project - Secretarial applications, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Book Publishing Project - Statement of Operating Principles, 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Book Publishing Project - Proposed titles, 1952-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Chorus "Dumka" of New York City, 1952-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Congress Committee, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Criticism of Free Russia Fund, 1951 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Free Academy - Canada (J.B. Rudnyskyj), 1952-1953 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainians - General Information, 1951-1953 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Organizations - Other, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Students' Organizations, New York, 1952 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Student Fund - Proposal (Kulchycky), 1953-1954 (Box 5)
    - Ukrainian Women's Alliance, 1951-1952 (Box 5)
    - United Nations, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
    - United Nations High Commissioner, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - United States Government Agencies, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - United Ukranian American Relief Committee, 1948-1951 (Box 5)
    - V - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Voices of America, 1952 (Box 5)
    - W Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Whiteruthenian Organization - Other, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Wischnitzer, Mark, 1952 (Box 5)
    - X,Y,Z - Miscellaneous, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
    - Yeghenian, Ave, 1952-1954 (Box 5)
    - Bibliographies, 1951-1952 (Box 13)
    - Russian Organizations - other (Box 13)
- Community Files, 1951-1954; III
  The East European Fund ran a community based program, which supported projects such as an Occupational Adjustment Project in Boston, Cooperative Community Project in Chicago and Employment Counseling and Placement at the International Institute of Detroit. This series consists of information on these community programs in the form of progress reports, spot surveys, and self-studies..
  - Administrative files - Spot Surveys, 1952-154 (Box 5)
  - Boston - Occupational Adjustment Project, 1952-1953 (Box 5)
  - Boston Occupational Project - Reports, 1952-1954 (Box 5)
  - Boston - Pamphlets and other printed matter, 1951-1953 (Box 5)
  - Boston - Self-survey, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buffalo - International Institute Integration Project, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Buffalo - International Institute Integration Project, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Buffalo - International Institute Integration Project, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Buffalo - International Institute of Integration Project - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - Buffalo - Internation Institute of Integration Project - Questionnaire Replies, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Buffalo - Self-survey, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers (2 folders), 1953 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Pamphlets, photographs, etc..., 1954 (Box 6)
    - Chicago-Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Pamphlets, photographs, etc., 2015.035.001 (Item 2015.035.001)
      Separated Materials
      Special format items (audio, film, video, digital media, library materials, memorabilia, oversize, and photographic material) have been separated from the file and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - renewal requests, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Reports, 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Reports, annual, 1951-1953 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Reports - final, vol I, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Reports - final, vol II, 1952-1954 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Reports - final, vol. III, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Cooperative Community Project for Newcomers - Reports - final, vol. IV (2 folders), 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - Chicago - Spot Survey, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - Greske - O'Conke, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - International Institute Project, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - International Institute Project, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - Merrick House Project, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - Merrick House Project, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - Occupational Adjestment Project, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - Occupational Adjestment Project, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - Pamphlets and other printed matter, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland - Spot Survey, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland Projects - general, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland Projects - general, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland Projects - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland Projects - reports, 1953-1954 (Box 6)
  - Detroit - International Institute Integratation Project, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Detroit - International Institute Integratation Project, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Detroit - International Institute Integratation Project, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Detroit - International Institute Integratation Project - Reports, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Detroit - International Institute Integratation Project, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - Detroit - Pamphlets and other printed material, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Detroit - Pilot Project: Employment counselling and placement - International Institute of Detroit, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Detroit - Self-survey, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Detroit Project - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Flint, Michigan - Project reports, 1953 (Box 7)
  - Flint, Michigan - Project reports, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Flint, Michigan - Rural Integration Project, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Flint, Michigan - Rural Integration Project, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Flint, Michigan Project - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles - American Friend Service Committee, 1951-1953 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles - American Friend Service Committee, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles - International Institute Integration Project, 1952-1953 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles - International Institute Integration Project (2 folders), 1953 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles - International Institute Integration Project (2 folders), 1954 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles - Spot survey, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Los Angeles Project - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey - Resettlement Project - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey - Resettlement Project - Reports (2 folders), 1954 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey - Rutgers University and New Jersey Welfare Council, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey - Rutgers University and New Jersey Welfare Council (2 folders), 1954 (Box 7)
  - New Jersey Project - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 7)
  - New York - Committee on Services to New Immigrants, Welfare and Health Council of New York, 1952 (Box 7)
  - New York - Committee on Services to New Immigrants, Welfare and Health Council of New York - Minutes, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - New York - Pamphlets and other printed matter, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - New York - Project on the Intergration of New Immigrants, 1952 (Box 7)
  - New York - Project on the Integration of New Immigrants (2 folders), 1953 (Box 7)
  - New York - Project on the Integration of New Immigrants, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - New York - Project on the Integration of New Immigrants - Reports, 1952-1954 (Box 8)
  - New York - Services to New Immigrants in New York City, 1952 (Box 8)
  - New York - Spot survey, 1952 (Box 8)
  - New York Project - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - Friends Neighborhood Guild integration Project, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - Friends Neighborhood Guild integration Project, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - Friends Neighborhood Guild integration Project, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - Friends Neighborhood Guild integration Project - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - Friends Neighborhood Guild integration Project - Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute, 1951 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute - Questionnaire replies, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute - Reports, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute - Reports, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute Integration Project, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute Integration Project, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute Integration Project, 1954 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute Vocational Guidance, 1952 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - International Institute Vocational Guidance, 1953 (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia - Pamphlets and other printed matter, 1951-1953 (Box 8)